<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computing Resources Unit</title>
    <description>The Computing Resources Unit at the College of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences at UC Davis is one helluva mouthful.
</description>
    <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 16:05:08 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 16:05:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mac Hardware Standards</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Mac Desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apple iMac&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Processor: 2.7Ghz Quad-core i5 processor&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Memory: 8GB 1600MHz DDR3 Memory&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Storage: 1TB Serial ATA Drive @5400rpm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/media/policies/Apple-iMac.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF Factsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Mac Laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Apple Macbook Pro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Processor:  2.3Ghz Quad-core Intel Core i7 processor&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Memory: 8GB 1600MHz DDR3 Memory&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Storage: 500GB Serial ATA Drive @5400rpm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/media/policies/Apple-Macbook-Pro.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF Factsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 08:25:17 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/mac-hardware-standards</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/mac-hardware-standards</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PC Hardware Standards</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;PC Desktop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dell Optiplex 9020&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Processor: Intel Core i5-4570 Processor&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Memory: 8GB 1600MHz DDR3 Memory&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Storage: 500GB Solid State Hybrid Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/media/policies/9020-Spec-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF Factsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PC Laptop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dell Latitude E6430s&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Processor: 3rd gen Intel Core i5-3340M Processor&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Memory: 8GB 1600MHz DDR3 Memory&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Storage: 256GB Mobility Solid State Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/media/policies/E6430s-Spec-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF Factsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/pc-hardware-standards</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/pc-hardware-standards</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minimum Hardware Requirements</title>
        <description>&lt;ul class=&quot;no-bullet&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;Operating System:&lt;/b&gt; Microsoft Windows 7 Enterprise Edition (64-bit)
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;Processor:&lt;/b&gt;
		Intel Core i5 (Sandy Bridge or newer)
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Memory:&lt;/b&gt;
8GB DDR3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hard Drive:&lt;/b&gt;
250GB 7200rpm SATA 2.0 3Gb/s&amp;lt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hard Drive:&lt;/b&gt;
250GB 7200rpm SATA 2.0 3Gb/s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Network:&lt;/b&gt;
Gigabit Ethernet Card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Security:&lt;/b&gt;Trusted Platform Module 2.0 (laptops only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Warranty:&lt;/b&gt;3 Year Warranty (parts and labor)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/minimum-hardware-requirements</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/minimum-hardware-requirements</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should I get an Apple iPad?</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Here&#39;s what you&#39;ll be able to do:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read books (PDFs, iBooks, Kindle, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read magazines (Zinio, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read newspapers (various Newspaper apps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes (e.g. Evernote, but please don&#39;t put sensitive information here, as Evernote stores it in the cloud)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read/browse files on cloud services such as Dropbox, Box.Net, iCloud etc. (caveat: no sensitive work-related files should be stored here! see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logon to systems with SSH (e.g. the &quot;Farm&quot; compute cluster)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do basic math calculations (e.g. Wolfram Alpha), run specialized applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run an ever-expanding list of other interesting applications....&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What you won&#39;t be able to/shouldn&#39;t do:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Print (unless you get an AirPrint-capable HP Printer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse websites with Flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep local copies of files with personally identifiable information (PII) [see InfoSec policy]&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Explanation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPads and other tablet computers offer a compelling, highly-portable instant-on computing experience. There&#39;s a lot to like about this, and industry analysts talk about the &quot;post-PC&quot; era. With that in mind, please be aware of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPads are extremely easy to steal/lose, and very easy to break into. Passwords/passcodes offer very little protection from determined crackers. Specifically, we cannot make an iPad/tablet exempt from the reporting requirements of SB1384, except under the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The iPad is encrypted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPad must accept the security policies CRU has put into place for mobile devices, including setting a passcode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two things allow us to reliably remote wipe the device upon notice of loss/theft. The passcode is not intended to keep out a determined attacker indefinitely, but only to allow us enough time to remote wipe the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is obviously not perfect, but it&#39;s the best we can do while keeping a minimal impact to your computing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Recommendations:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to buy an iPad and want to connect it to the CA&amp;amp;ES Exchange servers, make an appointment with us to do so. Please keep in mind that the only support CRU provides for personally owned devices is connection to your Calendar/Inbox on Exchange. We will provide full support for iPads purchased with CA&amp;amp;ES Dean&#39;s Office (Center, Institute) funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any intention of using 3G in another country, go with AT&amp;amp;T which uses the international GSM protocol. Verizon uses CDMA, which is extremely difficult to find in other countries (you probably won&#39;t).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cloud Data Storage:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to access files, iPads tend to store data in the cloud. By &quot;cloud&quot; I mean specific services such as GoogleDocs, Box.Net, Dropbox, Apple&#39;s iCloud service, or other providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRU will provide limited support for folks requesting the use of DropBox, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRU has an automatic software install package that will install DropBox on your laptop or workstation (for the iPad app, you must install it yourself from Apple’s App Store).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRU will not provide support on the configuration or setup of your DropBox account or files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage of files with Restricted Personal Information is not allowed by UC Policy. In particular, this violates the CA&amp;amp;ES Dean’s Office Information Security Policy, located here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/computing-policies/information-security-policy&quot;&gt;http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/computing-policies/information-security-policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dean’s Office employees are, in general, responsible for any files removed from CA&amp;amp;ES data storage infrastructure (i.e. the servers and storage area network (SAN) maintained by CRU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files should only be stored on official UC Davis Box accounts. IET provides support for Box, but Restricted Personal Information is not allowed on the UC Davis Box account; for this reason, this service is unavailable to the UCD Medical Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files stored on DropBox are controlled by the Dropbox user account, and therefore cannot be backed up or recovered in any way by CRU. Clients using DropBox are responsible for their own backups and recovery of files stored on DropBox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the same reason, CRU cannot provide any technical support to resolve issues with files stored on DropBox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that DropBox has admitted that they have access to and will freely provide decryption keys to your data under subpoena. This means that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dropbox can read your files stored on their service at any time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law enforcement of any nation can read your files stored on Dropbox at any time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Recommendation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clients that take information off CA&amp;amp;ES servers and workstations assume complete responsibility for the proper distribution, backup, and recovery of those files (as with USB keys and other portable storage media).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Installing Apps:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, there are no known instances of malware in Apple&#39;s curated AppStore (the same is not true of Google&#39;s Android store, not to mention the third-party Android stores). Therefore, we have no reason at this time to restrict app installation on your iPad, provided that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You do not jailbreak iOS (this immediately opens remote root access to your iOS device!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You associate your iOS device with a personal credit card, rather than a University one&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last point requires further explanation. Basically, apps will be a mixture of business/personal, and by policy the University should not be paying for personal apps. Hence, in order to install them, you will need a personal account with Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, and more importantly, several applications now offer &quot;in-App&quot; purchases. This means that even though you are using a &quot;free&quot; application, clicking once in the wrong spot will cause you to purchase something (such as a new feature, or the &quot;feature&quot; of removing annoying in-app ads). There have been several reported cases of parents finding hundreds of dollars of charges from their children playing a &quot;free&quot; game with &quot;in-App&quot; purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Requirement:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, in order to adhere to University policy, we must have iOS devices (iPhones, iPads) associated with personal accounts and personal credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that out of the way, we&#39;re sure you&#39;ll find your iPad/tablet device to be very handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/ipad-advisory</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policies/ipad-advisory</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computing Equipment Lifecycle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
The Systems Architect or other CRU staff will meet with unit heads to determine appropriate levels of computer equipment needed for Faculty, Staff, and Student Staff positions required to achieve the business needs of the unit. Using the stated and/or expected budget for the unit, a computer equipment lifecycle will be established in which computers will be purchased and disposed of on regular intervals, and warranties will be purchased commensurate with these intervals to avoid issues with warranty-lapsed equipment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of warranty hardware will not be removed from desks nor denied support during the gradual transition to a 100% in-warranty environment. Out of warranty computers which are currently in service as of 4/1/2011 will be supported until they are replaced with new hardware. Out of warranty machines may not be introduced into our computing environment, for instance computers purchased from the Bargain Barn. Out of warranty machines which are replaced will be removed and properly disposed of through the campus Bargain Barn as required by UC policy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why this policy? Why now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As budgets grow tighter, we’re all suffering from a lack of resources to accomplish our mission in the College. Below are some reasons why this policy is fiscally sound for the Dean’s Office and its supported units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Out of warranty computers cause more and longer work stoppages. Work stoppages equate to staff time being paid for but not utilized. As we focus on completing the same amount of work (or more in some cases) with fewer staff, work stoppages become more and more costly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Out of warranty computers do not perform as well as newer models. Staff time is spent waiting for computers to complete even simple tasks, subtly adding to the cost of staff as a whole. Per campus Cyber-Safety standards, computers must be running software with the latest security patches installed, which in some cases means running software not intended to be run on older hardware at reduced performance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Out of warranty computers cost more to support. Support staff must spend more time on older computers to keep them up to date and functional. Grooming machines of old software versions and periodically rebuilding them from ground up consume a great deal of staff hours that could be dedicated to providing more responsive support for issues like printing errors, proactive maintenance, and speedier deployment of new systems.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Every unit that plans a budget for equipment replacement on a regular cycle will enjoy a “no surprises” balance sheet when it’s time to look at the books. If an in-warranty device fails it will not represent a financial hardship to the unit. The device will be repaired or replaced without cost to the unit, allowing for dollars to be spent at the time of the unit’s choosing instead of requiring an “emergency” allocation.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why can’t I keep my old computer for a new staff member/student staff member? It was working fine when I bought the new one.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is question we get a lot. Here are a few reasons why this scenario works against all of us in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Providing a computer isn’t simply a one-time cost at a cash register. A significant portion of the cost of providing a computer is the ongoing support of that computer. When you purchase a new computer and don’t remove the old one, you’ve effectively doubled the support costs on that seat in the organization, without any prior planning or notice. If you had a staff member who was moving to a nicer office in a building where you paid for square footage, would you assume you could keep the old office for another new hire for free?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;To be effective at work staff and students must work on reliable computers with standardized software. Varying versions of the operating system and core business applications lead to problems in collaborative work environments. CRU maintains compatible application stacks whenever possible but these issues still arise.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Part of funding a staff or student position is providing them with workspace and materials. Desks, chairs, staplers, etc. have a long usable life and can be replaced without much hassle but are still requirements. In the 21st century a reliable computer is also a requirement for productive work.
 
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What do you do with our old computers? If we can’t keep them here, can I take them home or give them away to a charity?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disposition of University-owned hardware is governed by a clear set of policies relating to inventory as well as Cyber-Safety. Here are some facts about the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;University policy requires that all computing equipment purchased using departmental funds have to be retired through the University Bargain Barn salvage program. We catalogue all old hardware and computers that we reclaim from departments and then we pay the Bargain Barn to come and pick up the equipment. The Bargain Barn attempts to resell hardware and computers in working condition (most equipment can’t be resold). If the Bargain Barn does sell the old hardware they keep the profit to cover their own operational costs. See: UC Davis Policy and Procedure Manual, Chapter 350: Supplies and Equipment, Section 80: Disposition of Excess and Surplus Property (&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/350/350-80.pdf&quot;&gt;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/350/350-80.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Equipment purchased on non-University funds may be redirected under certain circumstances.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In the event that we release equipment to any party outside the Dean’s Office, (including the Bargain Barn) all data including the operating system data will be securely wiped from the hard disk(s) to comply with security and licensing policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/07/07/computing-equipment-lifecycle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/07/07/computing-equipment-lifecycle/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Helpdesk Prioritization List</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Email service/routing outages&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Network service outages&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;AD Logon issues&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;File server connectivity&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Printing outages&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Equipment Purchases/In Warranty Replacements (work stoppage)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Work stop issues on DAFIS, PPS, AIS etc if this is the core job function for the staff member.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Integration of new units and centers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Installation/troubleshooting of supported software
        &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Changes to mailing list/group memberships&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Office client problems (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Adobe/PDF)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Email client problems (Web Access working) including address book cache&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Remote access setup assistance/info (VPN and RDP)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Other supported software misbehavior including phishing, spam, backscatter, crashing, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Equipment Purchases (non work stoppage)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Installation/troubleshooting of business software that&#39;s already on the terminal server&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cell Phones&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Support of research / data gathering software&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Moving of functional equipment to a new location&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Installation/troubleshooting of unsupported software&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Equipment Purchases/Repairs/Out of warranty replacements/Unauthorized purchases&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Quote requests for equipment etc. that we might buy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Support of cameras etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Setup of secondary or third work computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/06/07/helpdesk-prioritization/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/06/07/helpdesk-prioritization/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Information Security Policy</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;I. PURPOSE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section describes CA&amp;amp;ES Dean&#39;s Office policy and procedures needed to comply with the UCD campus Cyber-Safety computing policy with regards to the storing and removal of Restricted Personal Information from computers and other electronic devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;II. DEFINITIONS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Cyber-Safety - UCDavis&#39; campus computing security program and related policies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Restricted Personal Information - A person&#39;s name, Social Security number, driver&#39;s license number and financial account information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;III. GENERAL POLICY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Storage of Restricted Personal Information. Storage of Restricted Personal Information on computers on which it is not required for work purposes is prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B. Removal of Restricted Personal Information. Restricted Personal Information on computers on which it is not required for work purposes shall be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. Devices which may not store Restricted Personal Information. Restricted Personal Information may not be stored on desktop computers in the Dean&#39;s Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D. Devices which may store Restricted Personal Information. Restricted electronic information may be stored on server computers in the CA&amp;amp;ES Dean&#39;s Office as necessary. Restricted Personal Information may also be stored on laptop computers or other mobile devices as necessary, but the data must be encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IV. REFERENCES AND RELATED POLICY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UC Davis Policy and Procedure Manual Section 320-20 Privacy of and Access to Information
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/320/320-20.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/320/320-20.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UC Davis Policy and Procedure Manual Section 320-22 Collection and Confidentiality of Social Security Numbers
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/PPM/320/320-20.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/320/320-22.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber-Safety Web Site
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://security.ucdavis.edu/cybersafety.cfm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://security.ucdavis.edu/cybersafety.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber-Safety Policy for Personal Information
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://security.ucdavis.edu/personalinfo.cfm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://security.ucdavis.edu/personalinfo.cfm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/05/07/info-security-policy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/05/07/info-security-policy/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get an Account</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the forms to fill out and sign to request computing access in the CA&amp;amp;ES Dean&#39;s Office. Supervisors, please send the Computing Account Request form to computer support at support&lt;a class=&quot;email-link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:support@caes.ucdavis.edu&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;@caes.ucdavis.edu&lt;/a&gt;  and we will process your account request. Please print out the Dean&#39;s Office Computing Policy Agreement and the CA&amp;amp;ES Information Security Policy, have the new employee sign them and send them to us via campus mail, drop off at 38 Mrak, or scan and email them to support@caes.ucdavis.edu. Please be sure to include the user&#39;s valid Kerberos ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Request Forms (supervisor)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computing Account Request Form - Dean&#39;s Office [&lt;a href=&quot;/media/files/Computing-Account Request-Form-v1.6-DO.docx&quot; title=&quot;Computing Account Request Form - Dean&#39;s Office&quot;&gt;doc&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To be signed by the new user:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deans Office Computing Policy Agreement [&lt;a href=&quot;/media/files/Policy-Deans-Office Computing-Policy Agreement.doc&quot; title=&quot;PolicyDeansOfficeComputing&quot;&gt;doc&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CA&amp;amp;ES Information Security Policy [&lt;a href=&quot;/media/files/Policy-Deans-Office Information-Security-Policy.docx&quot; title=&quot;Information Security Policy.doc&quot;&gt;doc&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&quot;/media/files/Forms-CA-ES Information-Security-Policy.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Information Security Policy.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/documentation/get-an-account</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/documentation/get-an-account</guid>
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
        
        <category>helpdesk</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Out of Office Reply with OWA</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log on to Outlook Web Access at &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://365.ucdavis.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;https://365.ucdavis.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the top right corner of the window, click on the settings gear. &lt;span&gt;In the menu click on &quot;Automatic replies.&quot;

&lt;li&gt;Configure a temporary or indefinite period of out-of-office status, or turn off your out-of-office message.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/documentation/out-of-office</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/documentation/out-of-office</guid>
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
        
        <category>helpdesk</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mobile Device Use</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Supporting a large number of mobile devices with varying types of software and user modifications can be a costly task in terms of IT staff time and resources. To ensure the integrity of the Dean’s Office data, network security, and office staff productivity, it is necessary to enact a set of mobile device use guidelines. The policy will apply to any mobile device supported by the Dean’s Office Computing Resource Unit (CRU) and/or any mobile device connected to the Dean’s Office subnet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Dean’s Office mobile devices constitutes consent to public disclosure of phone and billing records.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only approved software may be installed and run on Dean’s Office mobile devices.&lt;/strong&gt; A list of approved applications is &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;resolveuid/8aeb316f-b45c-40ea-b309-186de446e253&quot; title=&quot;Supported Software&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;. Approval for applications not on the accepted list must be obtained from the Director of Information Technology prior to installation. Any application not on the approved list and not authorized by exception to policy is subject to immediate removal. Applications not on the supported list that are approved for installation will not receive CRU support.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All mobile devices supported must meet established configuration standards.&lt;/strong&gt;Configurations will be changed periodically and updated by CRU. Installation of software and software updates will be performed periodically to maintain system standards and integrity and to keep the total cost of ownership at a minimum. Any exceptions or modifications to the standards must be approved by the Director of Information Technology.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data stored on mobile devices and the use of mobile devices will be safeguarded.&lt;/strong&gt; Mobile devices connecting to Dean&#39;s Office resources will be required to have a password to unlock the phone after a period of inactivity not to exceed 30 minutes. Devices will conform to the ability to be remotely wiped should the device be lost or stolen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile devices inherently store data which may be of a personal or confidential nature. This data is at risk of compromise in the event that a device is lost or stolen.&lt;/strong&gt; If your mobile device is lost or stolen, notify CRU immediately by sending a ticket to Computing Support Requests (&lt;span class=&quot;link-mailto&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:csrequests@caes.ucdavis.edu&quot; style=&quot;padding-left: 16px; &quot;&gt;csrequests@caes.ucdavis.edu&lt;/a&gt;).We will do the following:

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your user account password will be changed. &lt;/strong&gt;(Mobile devices store your password for automatic synchronization.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CRU will examine all e-mail in your Inbox and any synchronized files to determine if any confidential information was present. &lt;/strong&gt;(Only mail in your Inbox or files in your Mobile My Documents folder are synchronized with your mobile device.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CRU will attempt a remote device wipe.&lt;/strong&gt; (This procedure is not guaranteed to work).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Director of Information Technology must approve changes or exceptions to the policy and has authority over decisions affecting mobile devices supported by Dean’s Office staff and/or attached to the Dean’s Office network.
    &lt;br /&gt;This policy provides conformance to the UC Davis Cyber-Safety Program and the UCOP Business and Finance Bulletin G-46. You will be required to sign Appendix A of UCOP B&amp;amp;FB G-46, and it is your responsibility to be aware of your rights and obligations under the University of California, Davis, Electronic Communication Policy (P&amp;amp;P 310-16).
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://policy.ucop.edu/doc/3420357/BFB-G-46&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;UCOP Business and Finance Bulletin: G-46, Guidelines for the Purchase and Use of Cellular Phones and Other Portable Electronic Resources&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt; (http://policy.ucop.edu/doc/3420357/BFB-G-46)
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/310/310-24.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;UC Davis Electronic Communications Policy&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;(http://manuals.ucdavis.edu/ppm/310/310-24.pdf)
    &lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Direct questions regarding this policy to:
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adam Getchell &lt;br /&gt;Director of Information Technology &lt;br /&gt;(530) 752-8008 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;mail-link&quot; href=&quot;mailto:acgetchell@ucdavis.edu&quot;&gt;acgetchell@ucdavis.edu&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 09:25:17 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/04/07/mobile-device-use/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://computing.caes.ucdavis.edu/policy/2015/04/07/mobile-device-use/</guid>
        
        
        <category>policy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
